<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[SIGJE]]></title>
  <link href="http://iennae.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://iennae.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-28T22:55:39-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://iennae.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jennifer Davis]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Idea Generation Summary]]></title>
    <link href="http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/07/28/idea-generation-summary/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-28T21:57:48-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/07/28/idea-generation-summary</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we had a CoffeeOps DevOpsDays Silicon Valley <a href="http://www.jendavis.org/blog/2015/07/27/devopsdays-sv-idea-generation-event/">Idea Generation event</a>, and I had a ton of fun. I led an <a href="https://github.com/chef/chef-summit-2014/wiki/find-your-voice">Open Space at Chef Summit</a> last year which included an idea generation exercise and I followed that format.</p>

<p>We started off in normal SV CoffeeOps style chatting around topics. We then took a look at the <a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/events/2015-siliconvalley/proposals/">current proposals</a>, reading off the titles to prime the creativity pump. I had everyone take 5 minutes to just think about their feels and any ideas. Everyone wanted to start writing so I pushed a little on that. We ended up only &ldquo;thinking&rdquo; for 3 minutes.</p>

<p>Then, for 5 minutes we used postits to write down ideas, 1 idea per postit. If you want to host an event like this yourself, figure out what works for your group. The most important items is that everyone gets primed through some mechanism, the process is explained with supporting tools as needed (whiteboard, postits, etc), and everyone gets the opportunity to share.</p>

<p>Because I know the folks who showed, I forgot to explicitly express &ldquo;This is a safe space with no stupid ideas&rdquo;. Sometimes I go so far as to say &ldquo;stupid&rdquo; is banned. This is really important to level set expectations around communicating within a group setting especially with folks who may not know each other well.</p>

<p>Since we were a small group, I changed up the format from Chef Summit, and we each shared an idea and then discussed the ideas for that round. Time flew by so quickly that we didn&rsquo;t get a chance to brainstorm through all of the ideas.</p>

<p>I did take a few minutes at the end to share Julie Gunderson&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v5yZXjBixys">Embracing My Sparkle</a> Ignite. We had gotten in a discussion about what can be shared in 5 minutes. My feeling is that an effective ignite means that you distill down your content to the most essential. You might not say everything you feel on a topic, but you say enough to start conversations.</p>

<p>With the permission of my fellow attendees, I&rsquo;m sharing some of the <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1d_bwz1Rfr6LNYOv6zK51DwZMtmHjV1vldbmty-CxAA8/edit?usp=sharing">talk ideas</a> that we came up with. If you are interested in adding your own, taking one of these and expanding on it, please do.</p>

<p>If you are taking one of the ideas, please update the spreadsheet and in the second column comment so folks know that you are planning on using that topic. If someone is doing an idea that you are interested in, just update the column with your name too. You might even consider reaching out and working together on the topic. Everyone has a different perspective, so it&rsquo;s entirely possible that you&rsquo;ll approach the same idea in completey different unique ways!</p>

<p>Note, that these are potential topics, not necessarily titles.</p>

<p>As a location, <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/crema-coffee-roasting-co-san-jose">Crema Coffee Roasting Company</a> has a great space, delicious beverages, gelato and friendly staff. I totally encourage folks in the South Bay to consider it as an option to do these kind of small group events.</p>

<p><strong>About the Chef Summit</strong></p>

<p>By the way, if you have the opportunity you should totally go to <a href="https://www.chef.io/summit/">Chef Community Summit</a>. It&rsquo;s much smaller than Chef Conference, allowing for deep dives on subjects from training to community building, from developing for a specific product, to learning to contribute as a new person in a community. There is one in Seattle and one in London this year.</p>

<p>While the <a href="https://www.chef.io/summit/seattle/">Chef Summit</a> does give people the opportunity to connect with Chef engineers, more importantly it gives people the opportunity to connect with one another. A key pillar of <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920039846.do"><em>Effective Devops</em></a> is affinity; the strength of relationships between individuals, teams, organizations, and even companies. Within the context of describing work, it is generally broken down into 4 categories: reactionary, planning, procedural, and problem solving. I think there is a fifth category that is often overlooked: relationship work.</p>

<p>Relationship work is a catalyst, facilitating all the other kinds of work so that it shortens the time to get other work done, reducing communication barriers, and building trust based on regard. <a href="https://www.chef.io/summit/seattle/">Summit</a> is an opportunity for people to build and strengthen relationships between organizations allowing companies to cross-pollinate ideas and technology, work on building affinity at a larger scale than a coffeeops event.</p>

<p>Affinity is hard to measure. Even harder is measuring and exposing the value of relationship work. I see the outcomes in the community as companies host their own <a href="https://pulse.target.com/2014/02/our-own-devopsdays-conference-inside-of-target/">internal knowledge sharing events</a> encouraging inter-company cooperation based off of stronger affinity. I&rsquo;d love the opportunity to talk about this with others in upcoming open spaces!</p>

<p>Thank you, <a href="https://twitter.com/ljl_geek">Linda</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/funjon">Jonathan</a> for a great evening of shared idea generation and discussion. I look forward to your awesome proposals!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevOpsDays SV Idea Generation Event]]></title>
    <link href="http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/07/27/devopsdays-sv-idea-generation-event/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-27T10:36:02-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/07/27/devopsdays-sv-idea-generation-event</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>tl;dr CoffeeOps - DevOpsDays Idea Generation <br>
July 28, 2015 7:00 PM to 9:00 PM at <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/crema-coffee-roasting-co-san-jose">Crema Coffee Roasting Company</a> <br>
950 The Alameda, San Jose, California</strong><br></p>

<p>As one of the DevOpsDays Silicon Valley (DODSV) organizers, I care about creating a diverse and inclusive event. As a whole, DevOpsDays organizers value the participation of each member of the DevOps community and want all attendees to have an enjoyable and fulfilling experience. DODSV has a <a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/events/2015-siliconvalley/conduct/">Code of Conduct</a> as used by previous DevOpsDays.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/events/2015-siliconvalley/propose/">The DODSV CFP is open and we want to hear from you!</a> Your views and experiences in enterprise or startup, security, database design and administration, development, operations, community management and more have value in improving the ecosystem, informing others of how to build strong, resilient teams in a sustainable manner while getting work done. Bridget Kromhout, DevOpsDays core  and DOD Minneapolis organizer wrote about this to a greater depth in <a href="http://bridgetkromhout.com/blog/2014/11/03/the-first-rule-of-devops-club/">The First Rule of DevOps Club</a>. The CFP for <a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/events/2015-siliconvalley/propose/">DevOpsDays Silicon Valley</a> is currently open until September 30.</p>

<p>Taking off my &ldquo;DevOpsDays SV&rdquo; organizer hat, and putting on my &ldquo;Community Builder&rdquo; hat for a moment, to help encourage folks who have thought about speaking but are not sure about their ideas, and to provide a space for folks who aren&rsquo;t interested in speaking but want to participate in the process of building a great diverse and inclusive local conference, I&rsquo;ve organized a special edition CoffeeOps event for DevOpsDays Idea generation at <strong><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/crema-coffee-roasting-co-san-jose">Crema Coffee Roasting Company</a> in San Jose on July 28, 2015 at 7pm.</strong></p>

<p>This event is open to anyone who is interested in brainstorming potential talk ideas, providing feedback about talk ideas, and connecting individuals who might want to work on ideas together.</p>

<p><strong>More information about DevOpsDays Silicon Valley</strong></p>

<p><strong>DODSV 2015 Dates</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Call for Proposal closes September 30, 2015</li>
<li>Schedule announced October 7, 2015</li>
<li>DevOpsDays Silicon Valley November 6-7, 2015</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Conference Details</strong></p>

<p>DevOpsDays Silicon Valley is returning to the <a href="http://www.computerhistory.org/">Computer History Museum</a> in Mountain View.</p>

<p>We are expecting approximately 510 attendees.</p>

<p><strong>Speaking Details</strong></p>

<p>Most talks will be 30 minutes; auto-advancing Ignites are 5 minutes.</p>

<p><strong>Looking for ideas?</strong></p>

<p>Can&rsquo;t make the meeting and looking for ideas? Take a look at our previous DevOpsDays events in <a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/events/2013-mountainview/program/">2013</a> and <a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/events/2014-siliconvalley/program/">2014</a>.</p>

<p>We are looking for fresh, current and unique talks that target a wide range of skill levels from beginner to experts on technology, culture, and community.</p>

<p><strong>Speaker Benefits</strong></p>

<p>All accepted speakers will receive a ticket to DevOpsDays Silicon Valley, including all meals.</p>

<p>Thank you Dave Dash, Jeremy Price, Jamesha Fisher for proof-reading this post! Thanks to my local <a href="http://www.jendavis.org/blog/2015/07/01/starting-a-local-coffeeops/">CoffeeOps</a> crew for giving me the idea to have this event.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working With Gists Within Sublime]]></title>
    <link href="http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/07/26/working-with-gists-within-sublime/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-26T23:47:28-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/07/26/working-with-gists-within-sublime</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/">Sublime</a> is a pretty sweet editor in combination with the Sublime <a href="https://packagecontrol.io/">package manager</a>. Today, I learned about the <a href="https://github.com/condemil/Gist">Gist package add-on</a>. Gists are a way to share work. Every gist is a git repository which means that it can be forked and cloned in the same ways. Gists can be public or secret. Public gists are searchable; secret gists are not, but they are accessible by anyone with the URL. Most of the time, I use gists for training classes to assign IPs, as well as snippets of code.</p>

<p>After installing the package, to interact with Github&rsquo;s gist repository generate a <a href="https://github.com/condemil/Gist#generating-access-token">new token on Github</a>. You can also configure the settings to use Enterprise Git.</p>

<p>All of the commands to interact with Gist require 2 key combinations by default. With the <a href="https://github.com/condemil/Gist">Gist package add-on</a> on OS X, Command + K is the first key combination. The second is dependent on the desired action. Command + K followed with Command + O will open up a list of available gists. Double clicking opens up a new window in sublime with the content.</p>

<p>To save the gist, it&rsquo;s more than just saving the file in Sublime, it requires the key combo of Command + K Command + S.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diversity in Lens - Optimism]]></title>
    <link href="http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/07/23/diversity-in-lens-optimism/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-23T19:26:20-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/07/23/diversity-in-lens-optimism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier today I was sharing my feelings about optimism and it being one lens to look through to view the world. Each of us make a choice about &ldquo;reality&rdquo;. We process a moment in time through our experiences and our current state of mind cataloging it for future interactions. Shared stories from others help us to further entrench ourselves in our beliefs and values. Even in listening to a story, we are interpreting it based on our own assumptions about reality and what the words mean. We assign context based on our own beliefs, often assigning values of someone&rsquo;s character over words and behaviors rather than viewing it through the subjective context that individual is experiencing.</p>

<p>The lens that we view the world through can be of optimism or pessimism; neither of which are inherently bad or good. Just as with a dev or ops role where it doesn&rsquo;t matter what role we are in as long as we understand the impact on business workflow; it doesn&rsquo;t matter what lens we are using as long as we understand its impact on our overall processing. The lens in place for a particular moment impacts our perceptions and affects the decisions that we make. When I&rsquo;m viewing the world through the optmist lens, I&rsquo;m driven by enthusiasm and energy seeing the opportunities and possibilities around me. When I&rsquo;m viewing the world through the pessimist lens, I&rsquo;m preparing myself for negative outcomes conserving energy until needed.</p>

<p>In 2008, I wrote the following for myself. I&rsquo;m sharing it because I think it&rsquo;s important that we start talking about and actively choosing the way we choose to see the world. Sharing our personal context helps others to understand our behaviors perhaps even seeing themselves in a different light.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Focus on the best. The brilliance. The love. The hope. The best of what your life is. When someone asks you how your day was, or what you&rsquo;ve been up to.. reply with the very best of what is. Don&rsquo;t think about the frustrating bits.&rdquo;</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s the advice I&rsquo;ve been giving myself. On these last few days of taking time off of work.. and really spending time on self, I&rsquo;ve thought about where I want to be and what I want to do.</p>

<p>So there is this possibility of getting laid off. The economy sucks. There is so much gloom, doom, sadness.. I could wallow in the depths of it. I could hurt with the internal drama of a variety of situations.</p>

<p>Not everyone is going to like you. Not everyone is going to agree with you. It doesn&rsquo;t matter. Believe in yourself, and believe in others. Believe the best, cherish your friends and loved ones, and do whatever it is that you feel driven to do.</p>

<p>I feel happy. Things are good. I enjoy my job. I have a variety of friends and interests and life is <em>rich</em>.</p></blockquote>

<p>These words still guide me. With time and experience I&rsquo;ve realized that it&rsquo;s important to share the experiences and my authentic feelings with people. Letting toxicity of experiences build up without an outlet impacted me in a way that was unhealthy impacting my health in a myriad of ways. I still choose the optimist lens; believing in me and believing in others. I am happy. Things are good. I enjoy my job. I have a variety of friends and interests and life is <em>rich</em>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sparkle Edition Washington DC Training]]></title>
    <link href="http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/07/20/sparkle-edition-washington-dc-training/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-20T11:18:49-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/07/20/sparkle-edition-washington-dc-training</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since I&rsquo;m co-chairing the Devops track at Agile 2015 with <a href="http://www.ddegrandis.com/">Dominica DeGrandis</a>, I figured I&rsquo;d take the opportunity to meet more folks in the Washington DC area to see what kind of different challenges folks are facing with implementing Chef and Devops in general. One way I&rsquo;m doing this is an open invite for early edition <a href="http://www.coffeeops.org/">CoffeeOps</a>. I&rsquo;m also giving <a href="https://www.chef.io/blog/event/chef-intermediate-topics-washington-dc-3/">Chef Intermediate</a> on August 10-11 and <a href="https://www.chef.io/blog/event/2-day-chef-fundamentals-washington-dc-5/">Chef Fundamentals</a> on August 12-13.</p>

<p>One thing that I really enjoy about Chef (the company) is that we make our <a href="https://www.chef.io/contact/open-training/">training materials</a> available to folks under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">Creative Commons license</a> that allows (even encourages) folks to share and adapt the content as long as appropriate credit and licensing is maintained. Every individual that does Chef training teaches a little bit differently in terms of style although the materials are exactly the same. The value in the training isn&rsquo;t the materials, but the conversations, interactions and space that is created by the actual class. Every class is completely different because the people going to the training are completely different.</p>

<p>Private trainings (trainings for specific companies) are really interesting because we can have really deep discussions about specific topics (depending on time) and it&rsquo;s easier to get people in a collaborative mindset.</p>

<p>Public trainings are also very interesting because I can encourage folks to cross the chasms between companies and share their individual challenges. I&rsquo;ve found that depending on the area that I&rsquo;m training, it can be harder to encourage folks to get into a collaborative mindset. (Shoutout to the trainings I did in Chicago where folks were 100% helpful. Extra kudos to Phaedra Evans and <a href="https://twitter.com/MarvinEStreet">Marvin Street</a> for going above and beyond in supporting their fellow students!)</p>

<p>My goals when training are to create a safe place for folks to learn, share and build connections. All of our trainings fall under the Chef community <a href="https://docs.chef.io/community_guidelines.html">code of conduct</a>.</p>

<p>In Fundamentals, my goals are to help folks understand the core concepts of chef, read cookbooks confidentally with an eye towards identifying good and bad patterns, write cookbooks, and debug issues that occur through understanding what&rsquo;s going on. In Intermediate, my goals are to help people to understand more about identifying good patterns in using chef through greater understanding of resources through writing lightweight resource and providers (LWRPs),  additional debugging skills, and basic testing while in the process of leveling up ruby skills.</p>

<p>How do you know whether you are ready for <a href="https://www.chef.io/blog/event/chef-intermediate-topics-washington-dc-3/">Intermediate training</a>?</p>

<ul>
<li>Do you understand what happens when chef-client runs?</li>
<li>Can you explain Chef terminology clearly without having to look it up? i.e. concepts like resource, recipe, cookbook, organizations, roles, environments</li>
<li>Are you comfortable with your editor of choice and navigating the organization of a Chef cookbook?</li>
<li>Do you have Chef DK installed on your workstation?</li>
</ul>


<p>A second thing that I really enjoy about Chef (the company) is the attention to diversity and inclusion measures. Earlier in the year we provided <a href="https://www.chef.io/blog/2015/03/05/apply-for-a-chefconf-2015-diversity-scholarship-by-march-13/">diversity scholarships to Chef Conf</a>. Additionally, we regularly provide training scholarships.</p>

<p>I have a diversity training pass for <a href="https://www.chef.io/blog/event/2-day-chef-fundamentals-washington-dc-5/">Chef Fundamentals</a> on August 12-13. Training includes a continental breakfast, lunch, and an assortment of beverages. Please get in touch with me <a href="mailto:sigje@chef.io">sigje@chef.io</a> if you are available for the days of the class, have transportation to and from the class, have a wifi-enabled laptop, a SSH/SCP agent (OpenSSH, putty/WinSCP or equivalent), and a text editor, and most importantly have an interest in learning how to write infrastructure as code with Chef. Please provide the following information:</p>

<ul>
<li>Name</li>
<li>Contact information</li>
<li>Background</li>
<li>Confirmation that you can attend Fundamentals training on August 12-13, 2015 at the MicroTek in Washington DC with a functional laptop.</li>
</ul>


<p>If you are interested, but feel you don&rsquo;t have the right skills please get in touch anyways. I will help you identify whether you are gauging your abilities correctly for this Fundamentals class, and also point you in the direction of resources that will help you get the right skills. One resource that is available to you right now is the <a href="http://learn.chef.io/">Learn Chef site</a> that will walk you through some of the initial concepts and prep your workstation to be ready for the class.</p>

<p>I also have a sekret code &ldquo;HELLO-CHEF&rdquo; that will take 10% off both <a href="https://www.chef.io/blog/event/2-day-chef-fundamentals-washington-dc-5/">Chef Fundamentals</a> and <a href="https://www.chef.io/blog/event/chef-intermediate-topics-washington-dc-3/">Chef Intermediate</a>.</p>

<p>ETA: Extra special code &ldquo;WDC20&rdquo; for 20% off both classes!</p>

<p>The conference and training start early, so if you are an early person and are up for some <a href="http://www.coffeeops.org/">CoffeeOps</a> time in the DC area let me know!</p>

<p>Sparkle On!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starting a Local Coffeeops]]></title>
    <link href="http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/starting-a-local-coffeeops/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-01T01:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/starting-a-local-coffeeops</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few years ago I met <a href="https://twitter.com/mariusducea">Marius Ducea</a> at <a href="http://www.chromaticcoffee.com/">Chromatic Coffee</a>. Afterwards reflecting on the time that I spent, I felt more enthusiastic about my work in the industry due to Marius being awesome and the mental engagement outside of the everyday.</p>

<p>Marius has been a key <a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/events/2015-siliconvalley/">DevOpsDays Silicon Valley</a> organizer for years and community builder within the Chef and DevOps community. His insight into a variety of current and future technology was interesting and educational.</p>

<p>The conversation allowed me to see beyond the perceived value of my role based on the the technology and cultural mores of my company, that &ldquo;ladder of prestige&rdquo; present in some organizations that ranks Operations staff lower than Engineering (and &ldquo;non-technical&rdquo; roles lowest of all). Being in the middle of my company&rsquo;s &ldquo;ladder of prestige&rdquo; led to a lot of pressure with little reward. I had been having problems seeing the value of the work I was doing or what impact it made.</p>

<p>Talking to Marius gave me insight about what I was working on. It helped me recognize that I needed a change and that it was critical for my mental health to connect with a larger community of practitioners on a more regular basis. I envisioned creating a &ldquo;hallway track&rdquo; space with intra-company cooperation; affording individuals a place to meet together with no agenda, to connect and share in an undirected manner.</p>

<p>Conferences have this informal hallway track; the conversations in conference corridors in between sessions and after hours. There are barriers to quality hallway track time: inclusiveness of the conference, costs of attendance and job flexibility.</p>

<p>If a conference does not have a lot of diversity, and the attendees are very cliquish, this can lead to people feeling very isolated who aren&rsquo;t already established in the community. Conferences that have a code of conduct and make other efforts to be inclusive can help facilitate individuals participating in the hallway track. Additionally costs of attendance and job flexibility, may make the hallway track unavailable to a majority of people in the industry. Any specific conference may only last for a few days, why wait a whole year to get the benefits of the &ldquo;hallway track&rdquo;?</p>

<p>I sent out a tweet with a location, time and #coffeeops and showed up. The first few times, only one or two folks would show up. As time passed more people joined and interesting discussions like <a href="https://medium.com/bridging-the-gaps/leveling-up-your-skills-51169238e0d7">leveling up your skills</a> were had. Years later, other folks have started up local coffeeops from <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Downtown-Seattle-Friday-Morning-CoffeeOps/">Seattle, Washington</a> to Sydney, Australia. I&rsquo;ve changed jobs, and as a remote employee at <a href="http://chef.io">Chef</a>, it has become even more valuable to me as water cooler time; that time to take a break and remember to breathe.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s also a place to share ideas in their nascent form allowing room for the ideas to grow to greatness through the contributions and challenges of the group. All of the folks attending CoffeeOps Santa Clara were critical in helping me shape my thoughts in the well-received <a href="http://livestream.com/devopsdaysorg/events/3044568/videos/52394934">&ldquo;Hero to Zero&rdquo;</a> talk on <a href="http://burnout.io/">burnout and &lsquo;heroic&rsquo; behaviors in the workplace</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.coffeeops.org/">Coffeeops</a> is a way to generate your own hallway track, cross company cooperation and individual improvement.</p>

<h2>How do you start up a CoffeeOps?</h2>


<ul>
<li>Should you start a CoffeeOps? How much community do you already have? Are there people looking for the same kind of outlet? Is there already something filling the gap? What is the density of people in your area? Do you have the time and energy to expend if this is completely new in your area?</li>
<li>Be patient, it takes time to catch hold.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s important to be welcoming, encouraging inclusivity as new people join.</li>
<li>Talk about it. Ask for help. Use twitter and mailing lists.</li>
<li>Pick a good environment for talking.</li>
<li>Have coffee and show up. More people will show up over time. (You can also drink tea or cocoa or have brunch!)</li>
<li>When starting out don&rsquo;t get too bogged down by formalities of rules and procedures. Code of Conduct is important. Any other aspect is open for discussion based on the group of people that come together. Some folks will make the decision to come based on an agenda. Others will be more likely to come if it&rsquo;s more freeform as they deal with other obligations before heading over.</li>
</ul>


<p>Shout out to all the Slack CoffeeOps folks who helped me polish my thoughts here, and for the introduction to <a href="http://www.gouletpens.com/ink-drop">Ink Drop</a> to help me in my quest for awesome ink.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uniball Jetstream]]></title>
    <link href="http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/01/23/uniball-jetstream/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-23T12:49:59-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/01/23/uniball-jetstream</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I purchased a set of 3 Uniball Jetstream RT 0.7 mm black ink in January of 2014. The first thing I noticed was the length of the pen was significantly shorter from the Safari that I&rsquo;ve been using. It will take some time before I can tell whether this is actually a problem or just a difference.</p>

<p>The ink definitely dries quickly. I can&rsquo;t see how someone could smudge this unless the paper was somewhat wet already.</p>

<p>On moleskin paper, it was more readily stuttering where ink seemed to stop.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Examing Writing]]></title>
    <link href="http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/01/23/examing-writing/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-23T11:55:55-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/01/23/examing-writing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a supporter of the <a href="http://www.thesparknotebook.com/">spark notebook</a> kickstarter, I&rsquo;m eagerly looking forward to the &ldquo;perfect&rdquo; notebook. I find the act of writing notes much more helpful to organizing my thoughts than typing in to a computer most of the time. The challenge is finding the right combination of paper, pen, and ink. When everything is in balance, the flow of thoughts is seamless. There is no thoughts blocked as the pen dribbles, sticks, or stutters across the page. Ink flows in a seamless concert without the fear of smearing as I pause and withdraw inwards to reflect.</p>

<p>When Kate Matsudaira blogged about the search for the <a href="https://popforms.com/notebooks-fall-short/">perfect notebook</a> it resonated with me for many reasons. The deconstruction of the problems of the many notebooks she examined illuminated an important process that I hadn&rsquo;t thought through before especially around keeping track of what works, why, and how it could be better. I don&rsquo;t think there is a &ldquo;one&rdquo; perfect notebook, but I think the <a href="http://www.thesparknotebook.com/">spark notebook</a> is perfect for organization of goals, time keeping and the &ldquo;big&rdquo; ideas in daily work life.</p>

<p>When the spark notebook delivery email came out, I realized that I wanted to know more about the writing utensils people use and prefer to write with. I tweeted out and the twitterverse responded.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p>what is the recommended pen to use with my soon to be here perfect notebook :) <a href="https://twitter.com/katemats">@katemats</a></p>&mdash; Jennifer (@sigje) <a href="https://twitter.com/sigje/status/558101746208493568">January 22, 2015</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Generally I try pens out and then forget what worked and didn&rsquo;t. So I&rsquo;m going to try out some of the suggestions and share my experiences.</p>

<p><strong> Lamy Safari Fountain Pen </strong></p>

<p>Back in April 2014 at Chef Conf, <a href="https://twitter.com/isafarnik">@isafarnik</a> let me borrow his Lamy Safari. It flowed, was a great width for me in my hand and wrote nicely in my moleskin.</p>

<p>I purchased the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0002T401Y/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=B0002T401Y&linkCode=as2&tag=sigjesspace-20&linkId=VD7GXIAUV7QRUYMT">Lamy Safari Charcoal Fountain Pen</a><img src="http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=sigjesspace-20&l=as2&o=1&a=B0002T401Y" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /> (along with a second blue one) and it&rsquo;s been my go to pen since then.</p>

<p>I also have tried out different ink with the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0019W4EIW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=B0019W4EIW&linkCode=as2&tag=sigjesspace-20&linkId=VWI4SOYVWBXFKCGT">Lamy Safari Converter Z24</a><img src="http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=sigjesspace-20&l=as2&o=1&a=B0019W4EIW" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /> and <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00BZ28JDW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=B00BZ28JDW&linkCode=as2&tag=sigjesspace-20&linkId=VBG3ZQMCTOPX2SXP">Lamy Refills by Monteverde Rainbow Fountain Pen Cartridge</a><img src="http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=sigjesspace-20&l=as2&o=1&a=B00BZ28JDW" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />.</p>

<p>In the converter cartridge, I used <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000WJAJQ4/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=B000WJAJQ4&linkCode=as2&tag=sigjesspace-20&linkId=3MYQARAGEZLVGZ5X">Noodlers Polar Blue Eternal Ink</a><img src="http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=sigjesspace-20&l=as2&o=1&a=B000WJAJQ4" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />.</p>

<p><strong>The good</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li>Pen is a great width for my hand.</li>
<li>Ink flows easily.</li>
<li>My handwriting is improved just from feeling like I&rsquo;m writing with something substantial.</li>
<li>The Lamy ink and the Noodlers Polar Blue ink are great colors.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>The problems</strong>:</p>

<p><strong><em> The Ink </em></strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The ink can smear if touched right after, so if I pause or am writing too quickly &ndash; smudge.</li>
<li>The ink bleeds through on most papers. I received the &ldquo;perfect&rdquo; notebook at a conference that did NOT which was amazing (yay for conference swag of good notebooks!). A notebook I got from a Google event has also been great. It works &ldquo;ok&rdquo; in moleskin notebooks.</li>
<li>The Monteverde Rainbow ink has some not great colors. I should have figured out what maps to what, but for example the red wasn&rsquo;t RED, and the color I&rsquo;m currently trying out is a murky brown.</li>
</ul>


<p>Due to the first problem, I tend to write a bit differently filling in the top of the back and front of facing pages and then filling in below.</p>

<p><strong><em> The Pen </em></strong></p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t really pay attention too much to the fact that I get ink all over me most of the time. I&rsquo;ve noticed this with most pens. I noticed that my blue Lamy was more messy than the black pen. After examining the nib closely I think that there might actually be a defect in the nib. <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/fountainpens/comments/1uhn2t/really_bad_ink_creep_on_lamy_safari/">When I did some google searches</a> which led me to <a href="http://www.richardspens.com/?page=ref/ttp/creeps.htm">A case of the Creeps</a>. So it could be a mixmatch between the ink and the nib (which is why I purchased the different ink to try out). Essentially, I need to find a &ldquo;less wet&rdquo; ink to try out with the safari to see whether the experience changes.</p>

<p>In future posts, I&rsquo;ll take a look at the Unball JetStream, Bic Atlantis, PaperMate InkJoy, Uniball Signo 207, and Le Pens.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress Tips to Myself]]></title>
    <link href="http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/01/04/octopress-tips-to-myself/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-04T00:20:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/01/04/octopress-tips-to-myself</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When building from source to add new posts.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>git clone git@github.com:REPO
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span><span class="nb">cd </span>REPO
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>git checkout -b <span class="nb">source </span>origin/source
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>git clone git@github.com:iennae/iennae.github.io.git _deploy
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>rake new_post<span class="o">[</span><span class="s2">&quot;TITLE&quot;</span><span class="o">]</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Write blog entry.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>rake generate
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>rake deploy
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>git add .
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>git commit -m <span class="s1">&#39;MESSAGE&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>git push origin <span class="nb">source</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>For zsh issues for <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/issues/117">rake new_post</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Hike of 2015: Nisene Marks SP]]></title>
    <link href="http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/01/03/first-hike-of-2015-nisene-marks-sp/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-03T23:12:22-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/01/03/first-hike-of-2015-nisene-marks-sp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A little over seven years ago I was starting a new job. At the time I was 3 years into a health journey and had a goal of doing 25 hikes in 1 year. In 2009, I hiked my longest single day hike of 14 miles across two parks.</p>

<p><img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3453/3393516147_e760d05d33_n.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Over time being the single point of failure at work meant that I was not able to spend weekends hiking. Somewhere along the way, job stress combined with appendicitis and complications from surgery led to a state of low energy, high pain and not a lot of positive fueling activities.</p>

<p>In 2014, I joined Chef. All of a sudden some of the barriers that were in place fell away. Admittedly some of these were self imposed based on my own (high) expectations of my work. I started physical therapy and celebrated being able to walk further month by month.</p>

<p>For the last 3 weeks I have been on vacation and taking advantage of it in part by getting back into hiking. Each year for the last few years I&rsquo;ve set a reading goal on Goodreads that I have accomplished, this year I&rsquo;m bringing back my hiking goals! Rather than setting a number of hikes, my goal is to be able to hike <strong>15 miles</strong> in a single day by December 2015.</p>

<p>Today George, Brian and myself went on our first hike of 2015 at <a href="http://www.parks.ca.gov/?page_id=666">The Forest of Nisene Marks State Park</a> which is a few miles north of Aptos. It was relatively short as I&rsquo;m still sore from the last hike of 2014. Even though I&rsquo;ve lived in the Bay area for years, until this past December I&rsquo;ve never gone to this park. It&rsquo;s about an hour away from home and actually has a nicer area to walk with your dog than Henry Cowell. There are not great bathroom facilities here so not a great park for young families and long trips. The toilet at the trail head is enclosed in a small dark, dank building with the corpses of hundreds of flies on sticky paper hanging over your head. Paths are also not well marked. Lower areas allow dogs on leashes but past the &ldquo;Winter Gate&rdquo; dogs are only allowed on the fire road. Some of the trails cross the creek, and the expectation is to cross logs or rocks or wade.</p>

<p>Second growth redwoods line the road past the locked &ldquo;Winter Gate&rdquo;. There are also some eucalyptus trees. The creek burbles along to the side. Mary Easton Picnic area is very quiet with lots of picnic tables and another small dark less dank toilet stop.</p>

<p>We didn&rsquo;t see most of the items on this <a href="http://www.inaturalist.org/check_lists/6438-The-Forest-of-Nisene-Marks-State-Park-Check-List">checklist</a> but we did see Oyster mushrooms! Apparently there is a yearly <a href="http://ffsc.us/fair/2015/about">Fungus Fair</a> coming up next weekend where you can learn about the different fungi in the forest. We did see quite a bit of English Ivy which appears to be an invasive species.</p>

<p>Later this year we hope to hike up to the <a href="http://www.parks.ca.gov/pages/666/files/TheForestNiseneMarksWebBroch2012.pdf">1989 Loma Prieta Earthquake epicenter</a>. This is in a no-dog area part of the park so it will have to be a no-dog hiking day.</p>

<p>Overall this was a great adventure. I can easily see us coming back multiple times as I build back my stamina. There are short and long hikes with a wide range of experiences. The Aptos Creek Fire Road between the Steel Bridge to the Mary Easton Picnic area is mostly flat with a small bit of elevation towards the end. Past this area there is a gate that marks where dogs aren&rsquo;t allowed (and they aren&rsquo;t allowed on the Porter Trail or the West Ridge Trail). The Terrace Trail, and Oak Ridge Trail both have a small bit of elevation. While our hike was short, there is so much more for us to do here including hiking all the way out to the Soquel Demonstration State forest.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m really glad that my current job allows for me to even consider the idea of working towards this goal for myself. With the additional travel for clients and conferences there is potential for me to explore other areas as well. I am privileged to live in an area that continues to develop additional trails and parks to explore. I&rsquo;m looking forward to finding out about other places that have trails to explore. If you have recommendations for your favorite areas to hike please do share!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
