<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[SIGJE]]></title>
  <link href="http://iennae.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://iennae.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-12T13:34:49-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://iennae.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jennifer Davis]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chef Conf 2015 Extended Deadline January 13]]></title>
    <link href="http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/chef-conf-2015-extended-deadline-january-13/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-12T13:34:03-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/chef-conf-2015-extended-deadline-january-13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Chef Conf 2015 Extended Deadline January 13</h1>

<p><a href="http://chefconf.com">Chef Conf 2015</a> is coming at the end of March! I joined Chef last year, and Chef Conf 2014 was my first Chef Conference. As an employee, I got to see behind the scenes. I was introduced to this idea of having Speaker Liasons and Room Captains that smooth out the speaker experience. Barry Crist (Chef&rsquo;s CEO) and Adam Jacob (Chef&rsquo;s CTO) had human focused talks which set the tone for the conference. The Chef community as a whole is one of the most encouraging, and helpful communities I&rsquo;ve been a part of yet it has one of the same problems that other technical communities have in terms of diversity.</p>

<p>The conference has a <a href="https://www.chef.io/blog/chefconfcodeofconduct/">code of conduct</a>. Separately we also have a community <a href="https://github.com/opscode/chef-rfc/blob/master/rfc020-community-guidelines.md">code of conduct</a>.</p>

<h2>Chef Conf 2015 Dates</h2>

<ul>
<li>January 13 2-5PM PST Open Office Hours</li>
<li>January 15 11:59PM PST <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1i-jMg8jqJ_Z3JkkOELIdXXfdsf743uITcbRcrWF_XTQ/viewform">Submission Portal Closes</a>.</li>
<li>January 21 11:59PM PST Speakers notified of acceptance.</li>
<li>March 31 - April 2 Chef Conf 2015</li>
</ul>


<h2>Conference Details</h2>

<p>Chef Conf 2015 will be held at the Santa Clara Convention Center in Santa Clara, California (right next to the Levi Stadium home to the San Francisco 49ers) from March 31 to April 2. Early bird pricing is $1095. After January 31, the conference is $1395.</p>

<h2>Speaking Details</h2>

<p>We have 3 type of speaking slots, 40 minute talks, 5 minute lightning talks, and 2-3 hour workshops.</p>

<p>You can check out the <a href="http://chefconf2014.busyconf.com/schedule">2014 schedule</a> for last years accepted talks. For other ideas, you can also take a look at the topics that were discussed at <a href="https://github.com/opscode/chef-summit-2014/wiki">Chef Summit 2014</a> during the open sessions.</p>

<h2>Speaker Benefits</h2>

<p>If your proposal is accepted, you will receive a ticket to Chef Conf including all meals. Please let us know about any food allergies. We do provide vegan and gluten free options by default.</p>

<p>You will have access to a Speaker Liason who will assist you onsite. For example if you run into problems like a forgotten laptop dongle, or your laptop breaks at the last minute, ping your Speaker Liason. There will also be two assigned Room Captains who will introduce your talk.</p>

<p>If you are a first time speaker, we will connect you with a mentor to help you.</p>

<p>If your proposal is NOT accepted, we do provide a discount code to Chef Conf.</p>

<h2>Talk Selection</h2>

<p>Talks are reviewed, discussed and voted on by a diverse group of Chef employees. By January 21, speakers will be notified of their acceptance.
We do get a large number of submissions which means that we can&rsquo;t accept every talk. If your talk is not accepted it does not mean that it&rsquo;s not a good talk. We encourage you to submit your proposal to other conferences and meetup groups in your area as well.</p>

<h2>Open Office Hours</h2>

<p>Need help with idea generation or your talk proposal? Contact [Jennifer Davis]<a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#105;&#x6c;&#x74;&#111;&#x3a;&#x73;&#105;&#103;&#x6a;&#101;&#x40;&#99;&#x68;&#x65;&#102;&#x2e;&#105;&#x6f;">&#x73;&#x69;&#103;&#x6a;&#x65;&#64;&#x63;&#104;&#101;&#102;&#x2e;&#x69;&#111;</a> to schedule a 10-20 minute slot on Tuesday, January 13 from 2-5pm.</p>

<p>Is there other information you would like to know? Let us know <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#x69;&#x6c;&#116;&#111;&#x3a;&#99;&#x68;&#x65;&#x66;&#x63;&#111;&#x6e;&#x66;&#64;&#x63;&#104;&#x65;&#x66;&#46;&#x69;&#111;">&#x63;&#104;&#101;&#x66;&#99;&#111;&#110;&#102;&#x40;&#99;&#x68;&#x65;&#102;&#x2e;&#105;&#x6f;</a>.
<a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1i-jMg8jqJ_Z3JkkOELIdXXfdsf743uITcbRcrWF_XTQ/viewform">Submit your proposal by Thursday January 15</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress Tips to Myself]]></title>
    <link href="http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/01/04/octopress-tips-to-myself/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-04T00:20:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/01/04/octopress-tips-to-myself</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Because _deploy doesn&rsquo;t get committed to source, when building from source to add new posts:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>git clone git@github.com:REPO
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span><span class="nb">cd </span>REPO
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>git checkout -b <span class="nb">source </span>origin/source
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>git clone git@github.com:REPO _deploy
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>rake new_post<span class="o">[</span><span class="s2">&quot;TITLE&quot;</span><span class="o">]</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Write blog entry.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>rake generate
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>rake deploy
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>git add .
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>git commit -m <span class="s1">&#39;MESSAGE&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>git push origin <span class="nb">source</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>For zsh issues for <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/issues/117">rake new_post</a>.</p>

<p>For custom domains, CNAME should be added to source/</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Hike of 2015: Nisene Marks SP]]></title>
    <link href="http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/01/03/first-hike-of-2015-nisene-marks-sp/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-03T23:12:22-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://iennae.github.io/blog/2015/01/03/first-hike-of-2015-nisene-marks-sp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A little over seven years ago I was starting a new job. At the time I was 3 years into a health journey and had a goal of doing 25 hikes in 1 year. In 2009, I hiked my longest single day hike of 14 miles across two parks.</p>

<p><img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3453/3393516147_e760d05d33_n.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Over time being the single point of failure at work meant that I was not able to spend weekends hiking. Somewhere along the way, job stress combined with appendicitis and complications from surgery led to a state of low energy, high pain and not a lot of positive fueling activities.</p>

<p>In 2014, I joined Chef. All of a sudden some of the barriers that were in place fell away. Admittedly some of these were self imposed based on my own (high) expectations of my work. I started physical therapy and celebrated being able to walk further month by month.</p>

<p>For the last 3 weeks I have been on vacation and taking advantage of it in part by getting back into hiking. Each year for the last few years I&rsquo;ve set a reading goal on Goodreads that I have accomplished, this year I&rsquo;m bringing back my hiking goals! Rather than setting a number of hikes, my goal is to be able to hike <strong>15 miles</strong> in a single day by December 2015.</p>

<p>Today George, Brian and myself went on our first hike of 2015 at <a href="http://www.parks.ca.gov/?page_id=666">The Forest of Nisene Marks State Park</a> which is a few miles north of Aptos. It was relatively short as I&rsquo;m still sore from the last hike of 2014. Even though I&rsquo;ve lived in the Bay area for years, until this past December I&rsquo;ve never gone to this park. It&rsquo;s about an hour away from home and actually has a nicer area to walk with your dog than Henry Cowell. There are not great bathroom facilities here so not a great park for young families and long trips. The toilet at the trail head is enclosed in a small dark, dank building with the corpses of hundreds of flies on sticky paper hanging over your head. Paths are also not well marked. Lower areas allow dogs on leashes but past the &ldquo;Winter Gate&rdquo; dogs are only allowed on the fire road. Some of the trails cross the creek, and the expectation is to cross logs or rocks or wade.</p>

<p>Second growth redwoods line the road past the locked &ldquo;Winter Gate&rdquo;. There are also some eucalyptus trees. The creek burbles along to the side. Mary Easton Picnic area is very quiet with lots of picnic tables and another small dark less dank toilet stop.</p>

<p>We didn&rsquo;t see most of the items on this <a href="http://www.inaturalist.org/check_lists/6438-The-Forest-of-Nisene-Marks-State-Park-Check-List">checklist</a> but we did see Oyster mushrooms! Apparently there is a yearly <a href="http://ffsc.us/fair/2015/about">Fungus Fair</a> coming up next weekend where you can learn about the different fungi in the forest. We did see quite a bit of English Ivy which appears to be an invasive species.</p>

<p>Later this year we hope to hike up to the <a href="http://www.parks.ca.gov/pages/666/files/TheForestNiseneMarksWebBroch2012.pdf">1989 Loma Prieta Earthquake epicenter</a>. This is in a no-dog area part of the park so it will have to be a no-dog hiking day.</p>

<p>Overall this was a great adventure. I can easily see us coming back multiple times as I build back my stamina. There are short and long hikes with a wide range of experiences. The Aptos Creek Fire Road between the Steel Bridge to the Mary Easton Picnic area is mostly flat with a small bit of elevation towards the end. Past this area there is a gate that marks where dogs aren&rsquo;t allowed (and they aren&rsquo;t allowed on the Porter Trail or the West Ridge Trail). The Terrace Trail, and Oak Ridge Trail both have a small bit of elevation. While our hike was short, there is so much more for us to do here including hiking all the way out to the Soquel Demonstration State forest.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m really glad that my current job allows for me to even consider the idea of working towards this goal for myself. With the additional travel for clients and conferences there is potential for me to explore other areas as well. I am privileged to live in an area that continues to develop additional trails and parks to explore. I&rsquo;m looking forward to finding out about other places that have trails to explore. If you have recommendations for your favorite areas to hike please do share!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
